<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Tom Dalby</title>
    <link>thomasjackdalby.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Tom Dalby</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="thomasjackdalby.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Maze Generation</title>
      <link>thomasjackdalby.github.io/posts/2017-10-16-maze-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>thomasjackdalby.github.io/posts/2017-10-16-maze-generation/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few months I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting a fair amount with procedural generation. It started out from an interest in Roguelikes (a genre of RPG, check out the subreddit) but has expanded into a variety of more general areas, one of which is &amp;ldquo;maze generation&amp;rdquo;.
I&amp;rsquo;ve found that there is quite a selection of different approaches for procedural maze generation. In this blog post I&amp;rsquo;ll cover just the two that I proto-typed, but keep in mind this only scratches the surface of the available methods out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Python Module Hell</title>
      <link>thomasjackdalby.github.io/posts/2017-09-28-python-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>thomasjackdalby.github.io/posts/2017-09-28-python-modules/</guid>
      <description>A Python Module Hell Python has many good features, but I find some aspects of it frustrating. For example, I thought I fully understood the whole module/submodule thing&amp;hellip; just add a init.py file right? Well. After bouldering in with my C# namespace head on, I seemed to hit the &amp;ldquo;no module named ?!#! exception more than once, so figured I would sit down and learn it once and for all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weave</title>
      <link>thomasjackdalby.github.io/posts/2017-08-07-weaving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>thomasjackdalby.github.io/posts/2017-08-07-weaving/</guid>
      <description>Last christmas I was privvy to witness the giving of a gift to a young relative of mine, a weaving kit. Included in the kit, was a round disk, with a number of notches in the sides, and an arbitary amount of different coloured thread. The instructions, being aimed at the 3-5 range, were very easy to follow, and detailed how to make a basic weave. The concept was straight forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dragon Curves</title>
      <link>thomasjackdalby.github.io/posts/2017-07-30-dragoncurves/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>thomasjackdalby.github.io/posts/2017-07-30-dragoncurves/</guid>
      <description>So I&amp;rsquo;ve taken to reading a pretty neat magazine released monthly called Chalkdust. In it there are various maths related articles covering the whole spectrum, but one I was particularly drawn to last month was the concept of Dragon Curves.
Dragon curves are essentially curves, almost fractal like in nature. They take the form of a line making 90° turns clockwise or anticlockise, yet they never cross over themselves, and they also tesselate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public Blog b = new Blog();</title>
      <link>thomasjackdalby.github.io/posts/2017-07-29-blognewblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>thomasjackdalby.github.io/posts/2017-07-29-blognewblog/</guid>
      <description>Hello and welcome.
I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to pull together this blog, as an attempt at documenting my coding/software activities to some extent. It also comes with the nice side effect of being able to share with others, the wild and wonderful things I&amp;rsquo;ve found on the internet, and maybe improve my grammar a bob or two.
So, hopefully some (or all) of the articles I&amp;rsquo;ll publish here will interest you. I won&amp;rsquo;t lie and say I&amp;rsquo;ll publish anywhere close to a regular timeframe, but every time I find something interesting, or I script up something which I think may interest others, I&amp;rsquo;ll endeavour to post something!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>